TSION ZELEKE

My Contact

tsionzelekezerihun@gmail.com

+251-913-379232

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

https://github.com/TsionZerihun/

www.linkedin.com/in/tsion-zeleke/

Soft Skill

- python(Django, Flask)
- Javascript(JQuery, React, Node.js, Angualr, Express)
- SQL(MySQL,NoSQL,MongoDB)
- HTML,CSS
- C#(.NET)
- JAVA
- Docker
- Agile/Scrum/waterfall
- Visual studio code
- Anaconda
- wordpress
- ML/Al
- Data Enginerring

Education Background

ALX Holberton Software Engineering Programme

ALX Software Engineering Programme with a specialization in Back End Development Completed in 2023

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science computer science degree Completed in july, 2017

Achievements

- Arba Minch Institute of Technology and CSIT department for participating in CSIT club competition and exhibition with an Android application entitled "Android Based Campus guide
- "UNDP involve me" program for participation in a 1-minute filmmaking competition. •

About Me

I would like to introduce myself as a highly organized individual who has a passion for solving problems and coming up with new ideas. I have experience with a wide range of software and Hardware applications through academic projects during my first degree of study as well as the ALX SE program. Working on a project that changes people's lives is the long-term goal I have. I have the vision to enhance my country (Ethiopia) as well as Africa through automation and bringing new solutions and innovations.

Professional Experience

full-stack developer | Freelance

2022 - Present

- · Developed custom software solutions for clients using Djangobackend and react-frontend
- Build APIs with Node.js and Express.
- Currently working on a user dashboard software that uses .NET Core 7.0 for backend development
- · Built Ecom website using MERN stack
- Worked on a project on developing REST API for the Y-Maze test (Y-Maze test is a behavioral test for measuring the willingness of rodents to explore (new) environments
- Worked on simple Python projects
 - Extract images from Word document template and place them in folders with Python
 - Scrape data from the webpage and paste it into Excel
 - Building indexing and retrieval using preprocessed datasets

Volunteer Works

Improvement of the Ersilia Model Hub | Ersillia Oct 2023 Nov 2013

- Contributed to Ersillia Open Source Artificial Intelligence(https://github.com/ersilia-os/ersilia/issues/880)
 - o Install and run prediction for the EML
 - Literature review to identify models of interest to incorporate in the Hub (collaborative task).
 - Complete writing the Python script needed to run the NCATS-ADME server.
 - Deal with research software installation issues, including package dependency clashes.
 - Get familiar with a professional development environment such as MS VSCode.
 - · Look for MLs related to the organization, test its implementation, Suggest and document the new model

Django App Deveoper | Maroset

Nov. 2023- Jan 2024

- Build an attractive and user-friendly web app for the remote Jobs platform (Maroset) with the below functionalities
 - User registration and profiles, Job listing and search, Messaging and communication, Resume/CV Upload, Application tracking, Notifications and alerts User reviews, blocking and ratings

Develop Static Website | Degu Consulting

Dec, 2023 - Jan 2024

• develop static website using (HTML, CSS, JS) for a finance consulting organization (https://www.deguconsulting.et/)

Professional Experience

Agriculture Transformation Agency | ATA Data Analyst

Apr, 2019 - Sep 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Coding and running Automated Test Scripts for large data sets using VBScript in Excel
- Identify and acquire relevant quantitative and qualitative data using a range of applied and pragmatic techniques, and control data to ensure validity and accuracy.
- Plan, prioritize and manage workstreams from start to finish, including data collection, analysis and content development,
- stakeholder input and validation, and ensure required timelines and quality standards.
- Organize and conduct interviews with up to midmanager level stakeholders, plan and
- execute other critical stakeholder management activities.
- Ensure that the regional technical staff can carry out appropriate planning, evaluation,
- monitoring and reporting using a well-defined monitoring and evaluating system,
- aligned with the Program's results framework and following the indicators, data
- sourcing standards, roles and responsibilities and timeline established.
- Plan, prioritize and manage workstreams from start to finish, including data collection,
- analysis and content development, stakeholder input and validation, and ensure
- required timelines and quality standards.
- Mork with Directors and Senior Directors within the organization, as well as senior
- leadership at partners in government, multilateral and bilateral donors, NGOs and
- private sector companies, to execute high-impact, analytically challenging projects.
- 🛮 Independently work with regional counterparts to obtain and clarify all outstanding
- data needed for preparing ToR documents for different projects.

TAL Apparel | IT System Support Executive Oct, 2017 - Mar 2019

- Design and Implement the organization's Networks
- Network Database and Administrating, troubleshooting and configuration
- Maintaining records of software licenses
- Support and train the staff on how to utilize the company's software.
- investigating, diagnosing, solving computer software and hardware faults
- epairing equipment and replacing parts
- Obtaining replacement or specialist components, fixtures or fittings
- Checking computer equipment for electrical safety
- · Maintaining records of software licenses